hello I'm your host David Barnard and my
guest today is Eli WBAL head of customer
experience at captions an app that
empowers anyone to tell better stories
by generating and editing videos with AI
on the podcast I talk with Eli about
effectively scaling support for an app
why time to First Response is so
important and why you should treat
support more like a concierge experience
hey Eli thanks so much for joining me on
the podcast today thanks for having me
yeah so we both just got back from App
growth annual it's good to see you in
person yeah still a little jet lagged
but I'm enjoying my Revenue cat swag and
water bottle I didn't submit for a
Shippy this year but next year I'm
hoping to get one and bring one back for
the team at captions yeah captions is
fantastic probably would have won if you
would have
submitted also so cool that you had
actual Billboards like when you
displayed the winners of the shippies
there were nine of them you showed up
picture of an actual billboard in San
Francisco but I thought you would just
Photoshop them and then as I was leaving
the event I saw one just across the
street from the ferry building and I was
like damn they actually bought these
Billboards for them which was awesome
really unique and uh pretty cool to see
yeah we've been doing that for some of
our promotions and it's really cool to
have like actual Billboards and then be
able to go take pictures with them and
whatnot we did a uh Time Square
Billboards as well which was really cool
yes our whole team went there and took a
picture together it was really funny one
of our iOS Engineers was a hero shout
out to roel he was in the billboard and
it was pretty cool to see him like like
40t tall roel was pretty cool all right
well I want to kick things off with
something that you said when we were
prepping for the podcast that that
really struck me because I I it's kind
of a contrarian take in I think not just
a subscription app industry but maybe
just like Tech more broadly is that you
said don't just reduce and deflect
customer support and kind of the topic
we're going to be talking about today is
customer support but I think that's like
an important philosophy to maybe kick
off this whole conversation like why not
just automate as much as possible like
it's just such an afterthought for most
people so why do you think it's so
important yeah I think especially when
companies are just starting there's no
dedicated person to customer support so
like when I came to captions one of our
Engineers was replying to customers from
6:00 a.m. to 9:00 a.m. and then at the
end of her shift and so obviously this
is something that you don't want to do
but when you're finding product Market
fit you want to hear from your customers
as as quickly as efficiently as possible
and that really worked for us she would
see an issue in our intercom and she
would immediately just fix it in the
code because we were a four-person team
but as you get bigger you know you start
building out a team you hear from your
customers and you hear from customers
both happy and unhappy as well as
confused and a number of other feelings
that they're feeling but ultimately the
customers who reach out to you are the
ones who care right customers who churn
and cancel and never contact you they
don't care or or rather like you can't
do anything to help those people so I
always say if a customer is going to
reach out my goal is that they had a
improved experience even if we don't
resolve their issue even if we just have
a great response time and build somewh
before and let them know that we're not
a person in someone's basement trying to
trying to steal all their data and money
and and and rip them off I mean we're a
60 person team that cares about helping
all these people who want to create
great content so I like when people
reach out to us surely you want to
deflect some customers but not all how
do you think about that kind of balance
between the goal of customer support
being creating that great experience so
some amount of deflection like get their
answer as quickly as possible through
good support talks and stuff like that
but like where do you think the balance
is of like what things should be
deflected and then what things can
create a better experience connecting
with a real human I think repetitive
asks and by the way if the app was
perfect and had a great onboarding
experience and Tool tips and education
you know there would be no need for some
customer support but if a customer has
any question of any kind if that could
be automated whether it be with
self-help on our help center with
searching or browsing or some sort of AI
agent that can just answer those
questions in 30 seconds that frees up
time for our other agents to actually
build those connections with the
customers who are unsure if they want to
purchase if they're you know fishing for
pricing information and want to know I
mean don't forget if a customer reaches
out asking for if you have good better
best and they're interested in good a
customer support agent can also be a
little bit of sales and help them
upgrade or upsell to a different tier
that may be better for them so we like
those sort of interactions and yeah not
not all of them are built uh equally I
love this concept you you were sharing
with me about building customers for
life and how customer support is like
maybe one of the better ways to help
kind of reinforce that like you build a
great product but then actually
interacting with the customer can be
really meaningful I mean you Revenue cat
has tens of thousands of customers and
all of those customers have competitors
including ourselves there's no shortage
and the time it takes to actually become
a competitor to us is getting shorter
and shorter so I think it's actually
customer support can be a Moote in the
sense that if someone reaches out and
has a great experience we're able to
answer their question in 2 minutes they
find a competitor and out to them and
they don't hear back for 48 hours that
says something about who they are as a
company and I think people are demanding
high quality answers basically
immediately I know that when I call a
1800 number for my bank and you know
your call is important to us you know I
lose it I think customer attitudes have
totally changed but customer support
could be our competitive Advantage I
guess I a little bit more on the
customer for Life the c4l we have a
slack Channel called c4l and this was
kind of inspired by uh Tony Shay who was
the CEO of zapo he had this book called
delivering happiness that was kind of a
framework and a book that I read early
on that kind of changed how I think
about support and this customer for life
is really important with recurring
subscriptions recurring Revenue I want
to make sure and every one of my team
members everyone at the company how do
we make a customer for life and we
actually have a slack Channel where we
post screenshots of customers who say
your app changed my business I have I
have more views on my Tik Tok I've been
able to do this full-time and we share
those customer wins with the entire team
so that they understand who they're
building our app for yeah that's
fantastic and you're right like great
customer support can be a competitive
Advantage especially when again most of
the industry thinks how can I hire the
the fewest number of people how can I
Outsource as much as I can how do I shut
up these customers who are bugging me
you know when you when you have that
attitude it comes across absolutely how
do you think about the difference
between support and success when running
customer success and support inside
captions this term customer success has
been thrown around a lot and I think the
definition has changed I think it was
originally a coined in Salesforce and
they were the first team to have a
customer success manager customer
success team it was really meant for B2B
products and I think depending on what
sort of offering you're providing to
your customers you know there's low
touch high volume which is what we have
and then there is high touch low volume
which is usually more of a B2B business
so I think I don't know if it's exactly
like a lever on customer support to
customer success left to right but if
you're in a consumer and a prosumer
usually low dollar value subscription
you're probably more focused on customer
support if you're trying to build long-
lasting relationships with customers who
are spending maybe 20 50 $100,000 a year
on a large contract I think customer
success with a dedicated CSM is very
different than customer support and
those customer still need with a success
manager they still need support So
support and success needs to really work
in concert and that's at least what I
call customer experience encompasses
both the support and the success right
yeah so I think a great way to think
about it is let's just say there's
you're running a hotel right I think
it's the marketer job the co-founders
job VC job to build the hotel and get
people through the front door then once
people were through the front door
that's where I feel like I'm the hotel
manager and my team is the concierge the
bellhop room service I mean what we're
trying to do is we're giving customers a
three or sday free stay right during
their trial and what we want to do is
turn them in into an Extended Stay
customer and during that time some
customers may come in and want self
checkin with a little iPad they may want
to talk to someone and ask for a room
upgrade when customers get to their room
a light bulb may be out and I think it's
customer support and success job so that
if a customer reaches out to us and asks
you know for a new room that there's no
hot water in my sh show I need to
empower my team to be able to upgrade
them to a different room and I think
that's what customer support and success
is about is not just like building the
product but also ensuring this customer
has a really amazing experience and I'd
say David when's the last time some
someone said to you you got to stay at
this airport hotel it's so convenient
probably probably never but how many
times has someone said you've got to
stay at this Boutique Hotel I had such
an amazing experience the staff was
incredible we had dinner at a restaurant
one night the next day the same server
remembered my kid's name those are the
sorts of experiences that you have where
you're telling everyone you know you got
to stay at this hotel and that's
basically what I believe support and
success is gosh I don't think I've ever
heard anybody in tech support big
company small company analogize
themselves to a concierge that's
fantastic though I mean that that's a
very customer centered approach again
versus like so much of tech like you
can't get into touch with anybody at
Google if you're having problems with
your Gmail account it's like so many
people just brush it off but to think
about yourself in your customer success
or customer support team as coner that's
going to create a better experience for
your users it's just fantastic I love
the analogy and and just love your
approach and do think it's ultimately a
competitive Advantage for teams that
think about it in that way so thinking
about it in that way is great but you
you you actually got to like hire a team
and like develop processes and I know
that's something you've been really
focused on going from the four-person
team you joined to now I think you said
like 70 people at the company how do you
build a team and kind of instill that
attitude and also like keeping it you
know coste effective along the way yeah
I think when I'm looking to hire someone
there's like three key things that I
look for one is people who Embrace
change I think especially at a startup a
lot of companies that are moving quickly
we just move so so quickly it is one of
my big challenges to even learn from
engineers and product managers what's
launching when it's launching how many
people it's launching to and then I need
to extend that out update our
documentation and our macros and of
course train my team so I think people
that embrace the change and aren't
saying oh I can't believe this this
feature is changing again this is an
iterative process so I think I need
people who enjoy that and look forward
to say wow we're moving so quickly this
is this is great and then I'd say
curiosity shouldn't be overlooked I
think I mean I was very lucky early in
my career here my mentor and CEO took me
under his wing and said I well for a
little backstory I just traveled around
the world I I left I graduated college I
traveled around the world for a year by
myself with a backpack and when I
interviewed with this person you know he
said tell me about yourself and I said
well I've just been you know traveling
for a year and he said the whole
interview just turned into me telling
him country by country everywhere I went
everything I did and I was curious about
the world and he basically hired me on
that fact in that I figured it out I was
ious about it and I figured it out I
think you can train for your particular
app we're a video editing app we can
train on that sure it's great to have
someone who was a video editor but if
you're curious you'll figure it out and
I think that that really again should
not be overlooked and then lastly I have
this kind of other saying that when I
meet people are these the kind of people
that will push the trash down and I know
this is a little strange to think about
but have you ever been at your office or
you you've had been at a party and you
see the trash kind of overflow and
people just drop by and put a little a
little thing right on top and move on
with their life you know I want people
who are going to roll up their sleeves
and push that trash down and make room
for others it's not about them right
they could have put that on top and
walked away they're thinking about the
person after them who want to throw away
whatever they're going to throw away to
me that's like a huge indicator although
hiring virtually it's very hard to test
for this but it's kind of it's kind of a
Vibe check yeah yeah that's great and
then I think a lot of people you know
today in 2024
will hear that and think well why not
just use AI or AI is going to replace
all those people anyway why hire a big
team just train a bunch of Agents like
work on your your prompt engineering
skills you know how are you thinking
about the blend of people and Ai and how
to effectively use AI to provide that
kind of concierge experience I think you
used the exact right word which is blend
I don't think AI is necessarily
replacing all human jobs especially in
customer support I will say as an
industry I think customer support agents
will be one of the the most affected
Industries I mean think about your bank
or your airline or your IT company even
within within where you work I mean a
lot of this is just knowledge Gathering
and regurgitation of what is already
documented either internally or
externally so I think for these
repetitive tasks or maybe even easy
actions I think about it as a pyramid
where at the bottom you've got let's
call it eight agents and above them
you've got maybe two escalation people
and then maybe a manager and yourself on
top I think that bottom layer is already
able to be replaced and the question is
are all those tier one agents going to
be retrained to be able to become tier 2
agents or higher and so I don't think
like the tier one customer support is
going away I actually think this frees
up my team to spend more time with the
customers who need it so it's not that
these agents are maybe being like fully
replaced I think they're serving a
different function where they're not
just trying to get through the queue and
answer questions they have maybe two or
three or four times as much time with
each interaction to build rapport and
maybe create more of a human connection
and then I think I mean all of the
conversations so far even some of these
characteristics that you discuss and how
you hire a person is probably how you
want to think about training that those
tier one AI agents as well it's like
whatever kind of pre- prompting that
you're doing whatever kind of scripts
you're you're baking in there you should
be taking that coner mindset to the AI
agents because I mean what a crappy
experience so many of these have been in
the past the phone trees and whatnot and
like yeah it's finally getting better
but it can still be a really bad
experience talking to AI so even that
probably requires a lot of the kind of
similar thinking of what you've kind of
been talking about so far yeah I think
there's one tool that we've been really
impressed with over the past couple
months I did a full evaluation of every
single AI agent and chapot there is and
actually I think there's a slight
distinction I think a lot of AI options
out there are simply chat Bots where
they're telling you information and it's
very clear that they're a bot I think
there's a whole new breed that is there
will be a wave is is my prediction of
true AI agents who can empathize and
perform actions and do things like that
so basically i' I've went through a full
evaluation found a really awesome
company called parel they were actually
just two guys from Denmark who were part
of Y combinator they just graduated this
year summer of 2024 and they've been
amazing partners because they really
understand who our customers are and the
amount of empathy and smarts that this
has truly knocked my socks off and now
this AI agent is working in concert with
the rest of my team to basically Tag
Team every single message that comes in
if it's fairly easy to answer it tries
to answer it if it's too complicated it
can hand off and I think maybe I'll put
ask you a question for change David you
know when you call you know your bank or
you reach a chat agent online I mean
probably half of them are Bots now how
many chances do you give the bot before
you give up and ask to speak to a human
yeah not many I mean that was kind of
what I was saying like it's uh yeah as
you said they're not truly agents this
first wave of chat thoughts has been
pretty rough it's tarnishing those
Brands so like your to your points
earlier instead of like building a
customer for life you're you're kind of
pissing people off and I man I feel that
so 100% it's been mostly bad experiences
the few times I've had good experiences
it is when I have a clear question I ask
that question and get the response
without having to like read a bunch of
docs but it's like kind of a glorified
you know rag agent where it's like it's
just doing Google but better in pasture
yeah I think there's also like a clearly
not every customer who interacts with
our AI agent ends with age and they they
sometimes get escalated I think just as
you know I'm always trying to put myself
in the shoes of the customer and so if I
reach out to again my bank and I ask a
question and the bot did not understand
it they us like you know I'm sorry I'll
connect you with a human and then you're
telling the human everything you told
the agent all over again now you're
already like you were at zero right you
were neutral now you're below so that
agent has to do a lot of work to win
back your trust I think the way that we
have it set up is the AI agent is quite
effective and if it doesn't understand
or it can't answer or we've you know I
think it's very important to program
what not to answer right you know
someone says give me captains Max free
for Lifetime it can't just you know it
can't just do that or right anyway the
escalation piece is great because this
is a nice transfer and again like it's
all about working in concert and at
least if you get transferred to a human
agent the human agent has full knowledge
of everything that was spoken and talked
about before and you've been escalating
from a human to another human
essentially as opposed to oh this didn't
work out we tried to Sho you out the
door but you were you were too smart for
us now we got to connect you to a
expensive human I don't like that I
don't like that flow yeah I think
there's a a lot of Brands burning
consumer Goodwill with these really bad
flows that they think is saving the
money but it's not providing that
concierge experience that we keep
talking about as you've been building
the team integrating these AI agents and
doing all those things how do you think
about scaling up to providing quick
support and then if the tier one agent
can answer it AI agent can't answer it
immediately you know how quickly can you
get a two agent on and how do you think
about scaling that concierge experience
yeah I mean we have again we have like a
good better best uh scenario and we've
got trials on app store and play store
we we're on our web we've got stripe I
think what we have is a little bit more
customization so if a customer reaches
out to us we know whether they're in
their trial if they're a canceled trial
or if they're a premium customer and we
have rules where those customers can
either skip to the front of the line or
they can skip the AI agent completely
and even get reconnected to the agent
they last spoke with so I think it's a
little bit moving into customer success
it's kind of lightweight one to many but
there are definitely things that you can
do to kind of impress your customers
especially those that are potentially
paying more you know more Revenue per
year but yeah scaling scaling is hard if
were not for AI I think our team would
be twice as big so I suppose you know
what I was saying about taking jobs I
haven't had to let anyone go I think I
always want at least one or two human
agents at all again we do 247 support
247 yeah so yeah I'm not sure how many
regions there are in the App Store I
think there's like 186 maybe you have
that stat but we have at least one
customer in every country in the world
which also means language right so we
have an app that translates every
customer message into English we reply
in English it translates back to their
language and I think localization for
those that aren't just selling in the
United States or North America
localization is something we have a
really really big effort on because you
need localized App Store and Play Store
you need localized website localized
help center and localized app we just
made a big Improvement to our website
Brazil is one of our biggest markets a
couple months ago when we launched the
website in Portuguese we saw a huge lift
in installs in Brazil really really
makes a difference yeah so that's
localization I think really about 24/7
support I think customers are demanding
this even for an app that cost $9.99 a
month I think a lot of our competitors
don't offer any support or actually
what's very common is Discord support or
Discord support only I've tried Discord
I have my own issues with Discord but
yeah 247 support is for us is super
important and if you're not there yet at
least what I can suggest is try and get
to 5 days a week you know 8 hours 5 days
a week and then get to maybe 10 hours 5
days a week add a little bit of Saturday
and Sunday and then try and get 12 hour
support all seven days and then
eventually move the uh make the switch
to 247 I will say the only thing is once
you start offering 247 especially if you
Market that you have to keep your
promise but that said if on your website
it says great customer support customers
will say okay maybe they have great
customer support if you say 247 support
and you Market that and you put that on
your pay wall you might get an uplift I
mean I would I would argue that c
companies that are exploring with your
with your pay wall feature change one
word and just say support to 24/7
support and see if it gives you a lift
on checkout I'd be very curious we
haven't tested it because we already
have 247 support but if you are going to
do that contact David or may after and
let us know what your results were but
yeah time to First Response is super
important even if you're it's saying we
got your response we will escalate it to
the team once we're back on normal
working hours and by the way that's how
we first launched our AI agent we kept
our normal 8 Hour support seven days a
week and we had our AI agent on on off
hour support just so customers got a
friendly message saying we received this
and then when we came in the next day we
would reply to them so if you're if
you're really afraid of AI or you're not
sure it's right for you try it for off
hour support and you could Market 247
support right there it's a quick win are
you actually hiring around the world to
cover those different time zones now
that you are truly offering 24/7 support
how do you work that side of things
there's a common term called follow the
sun support and essentially you just
have one person in Americas one person
APAC one in emia and that's how we have
a set up to we've got agents all across
the country and actually two of our
agents we found in a really interesting
way one of them was a customer who just
kept on contacting us and telling us all
the feature requests he wanted and also
all the bugs that he found early on
which was very helpful and then we
eventually said you know would you like
a job and then we had another one of my
agents who's been with us for almost as
long as I've been here a year and a half
he was in our Discord and he was super
active and off hours people because he
was in India people would ask questions
and we weren't awake he would answer
them and he'd link to our help center
and all of his answers were unbelievable
we had no idea who this guy was after a
week I DMD him I said who the hell are
you and yeah so I mean yeah shout out to
shrenik and then we ended up hiring him
and he's been amazing I mean he really
he was a customer so there was barely
any training to do he knew more about
the app than I did he was a video editor
so again if you have a loyal customer
base you're looking to hire support
maybe I do have a piece of advice reach
out to your community you know tweet
we're hiring go to your Discord and say
we we're opening this position I think
you'll be surprised how many people come
out and either apply or refer a friend
for your job how do you blend that the
community aspect so is it a Discord or
do you have like Q&A like public like
kind of forum kind of style like how
does that fit into that bigger picture I
think if you're just launching and you
need consistent feedback and you haven't
found product Market fit yet or you're
launching so many features you need to
keep finding product Market fit I think
Discord is amazing I think and again
depends who your customers are but at
least for us we found a lot of customers
love Discord gave us feedback added
screenshots and early on in the company
when we were 10 or less people every
single employee was in Discord and we
would mention each other and answer our
CEO garv would reply directly to
customers and ask what if we did this
what if we added this feature and it's
kind of this iterative customer research
where you don't need to bother with
surveys or or setting up Google meets or
even paying people I mean people are
I've had plenty of people say you should
build this I mean there's no shortage of
people that think they can build the app
better than you so early on I think this
hord is amazing I think as you get as
your product becomes more mature it's
much harder especially as as you have
more customers because there's a lot of
noise and you know there's more features
or there's more that could go wrong or
more that we didn't do exactly the way
for their use case I mean the very
common question we get is can you just
make a button that does
X and it's like well we have this whole
strategy you know we've got 70 employees
we have a road map I mean sure we need
some quick wins and I think actually
that again shouldn't be overlooked which
is if customers are really loud about
something and they are constantly
talking about it and voting it if you
just sneak in a little bit of a feature
request or a quick win and the CEO goes
and says hey guys we listen this is
fixed talk about a c forl experience
those customers say you actually listen
to me I'm just I'm a nobody I'm one of
I'm one of all of your customers and to
get that sort of direct access to
leadership or product goes a really long
way so yeah again that's a nice quick
win that you can do and create customers
for life and Point did you phase that
out and then did anything replace it in
the interim and then at your scale now
with what tens of millions of of
downloads do you still have any kind of
community aspect we do our Discord is
still active I think it's kind of
changed from we were providing customer
support before but with our customer
base we've got iOS Android desktop we're
launching features we do AB testing
every feature we launch has a two-e
period where we test the variables and
make sure it performs better so if we
don't know who these customers are it's
very hard to support them so we
encourage everyone to send us a message
in the app so we basically tried to
Route all Discord support inquiries
directly to the app and take them
offline because it could also become a
little bit of a hate Fest where people
talk and talk but we manage all that on
our side with tagging and things like
that so the Discord is still active but
I think as you get bigger you can also
think about things like slack so I'm a
part of a really great Community Our
Help Center is built on this company
called mint lefi they're more of like
B2B but they have a Channel and I think
because we're a business and I've got
slack open all the time they've built a
really great Community where all of
their customers are sharing ways that
they're launching their Help Center or
Design Elements and things like that so
I think early on Discord as you become
more mature maybe take it offline and
actually maybe newsletter I think
newsletter might be a great way to keep
customers up to date with what you're
doing and then of course inapp
notifications inapp popups I can't
remember which app it was particular but
I opened up an app a couple weeks ago
and it said since you last logged in
here's what changed and that really that
really knocked my socks off because it
wasn't just here's what's new this month
here's what's new for you if you logged
in a week ago this one thing changed if
you logged in three month months ago
these 10 things changed and I thought
discoverability within your app is a
challenge I know for a fact there are
customers who've been using our app for
a year and a half for two years and they
haven't used half of our features
because they don't even know they exist
so that's something that we can
definitely do a better job of but anyone
who is you know iterating so quickly
don't forget to Market to your existing
customers not just new customers yeah
where do docs fit into all this so we
talked community and now you do have
great 24-hour support yeah how do you
think about docs and who manages
internally yeah another struggle
especially with things moving so quickly
so I'm ultimately responsible for
documentation but we moved to this great
platform which offers a lot of
translation services and localization so
again if we've got customers who don't
speak English you just need to have it
all of your content localized and I
think another challenge is just keeping
up with the the sheer Pace I mean I'm
always knocking on my uh product
manager's shoulder saying hey did this
feature go out yet or you know when is
this feature going out did we actually
changed the name of it it used to be
called this now it's called that it's
really important and I think something
that's changed in the 12 years that I've
been in Customer Support is I've always
written content for humans maybe a
little bit of SEO because that doesn't
hurt but basically human consumption but
again with AI chatbots and agents our AI
agent takes two sources when it responds
to a customer it takes Our Help Center
documentation because that has to be up
to date and it takes our most recent
human agent responses and then craft a
response so it's kind of The Best of
Both Worlds where you've got the source
of truth that is your help center and
your your documentation and then you've
got your kind of human element of how
would a human agent reply to this
customer and it Blends those two and
gives a really solid answer and then one
of the best things I heard is that one
of the reasons AI agents are better than
humans is that it has infinite
patience and you know I know David
you're a dad I don't think you have
infinite patience and I'm sure you'd
love Infinite patience but yeah I mean
that really goes a long way in helping
customers where you they've got all the
Time in the World to reply to these
customers but you've got to keep your
documentation up to date or else you're
AI agent won't be giving the right
answers nor will your team right cuz
when human agents reply to customers
they're verifying on The Help Center
that's up to date so it's really my job
or someone that you can have on the team
you actually want to be a choke point
between product and customer support
because you need to have the information
flowing both ways from product cross to
us here's what's updated here's what's
fixed and then back the other way from
customers reporting issues and you're
reporting issues back through linear or
jira or talking to customers so it's
really a a two-way street that has to
happen that's where I see myself yeah
how do you manage that side of things
I've been meaning to get into that it's
like not only is customer support about
you know creating those great
experiences for customers and being that
concierge but then in building a product
some of that feedback from customers can
be invaluable for building that next
thing so early on it was Discord and you
could just chat with the customer but
you know now that as you've scaled this
how do you think about kind of getting
that feedback tracking frequent issues
tracking frequent feature requests and
then surfacing that in a meaningful way
to the product team or or other teams
inside the organization
something I always try and advocate for
within the company is we're 70 people
we're all in New York City we worked
here 5 days a week we're a very uh
discreet group of people and we're
providing an app for millions of people
across the world from all demographics
and a
and all different walks of life so I
think reminding yourself that oh I
wouldn't use this feature or I would use
this feature the truth is you probably
really don't know and so you know it's
just really an important thing to remind
yourself when you're building these
products you do need to continually get
feedback from these customers because
nothing a customer says is inherently
wrong or bad I think you just need to
determine who is your core customer if
if you're getting loud feedback from one
group of people but those aren't the
customers you actually care about sure
you could ignore them I mean hopefully a
product will pop up that will serve
their need but you do need to stay focus
one thing I struggle with personally is
you know early on my career I wanted to
solve everyone's problems and that
probably went beyond just customer
support I mean you'd be surprised what
people what people dipe and ask for I
mean some people just you know are you
know want to talk to someone or you know
they they want to know that they're
being heard yeah but all sorts of
questions that come in I mean you need
to decide what is a priority and you you
just need to be aligned with your
leadership team and your product team
what information do you pass along and
what do you keep to yourself a lot of
times it's a forcing function of itself
once something actually breaks or
actually becomes so loud then you share
that with the team and something you
have to be careful of as a customer
support person is you can't be the sky
is falling person I was definitely that
person in the past and every time you
join a new company there's a new a new
chance to you know Define yourself but
that is definitely some hard Lessons
Learned of you know thinking the app is
completely broken works and it turns out
like it was only three people
right yeah understanding the scale of
the problem is is is important yeah so
we've been talking about what thingss to
escalate or not escalate and how to look
at those things but are there other like
specific metrics that you track and and
care about in running the customer
support customer success work yeah I've
hit on time to First Response already
which is super important I've definitely
spoken with colleagues who have 24hour
or 48 hour time to First Response in
touch maybe in some Industries that's
okay but for us we're currently at 58
seconds as time to First reply and again
that may just be hey we received your
message or our AI agent gave an initial
attempt at an answer but I think that
number really matters another one that
is interesting is contact rate which is
the percentage of customers of
subscribers who reach out in a given
month so again if you've got you know
100,000 customers and you've got a 3%
Reach Out that tells you something and
also really helpful for understanding
what your next month's inbound volume is
going to be again can help you staff can
help you scale but you know right now
we're at like a 3% which means 3% of all
customers subscribers reach out in a
given month which I think is a healthy
number I think if they're complaining
about the same sort of issues sure you
want to reduce that by passing it on to
the product team and fixing bugs and
things like that but yeah if you're at a
you know one and three or you know 40%
50% definitely a little bit scary but I
think any fluctuation is actually
probably more important to look at if
one month you've got a 1 and a half%
Reach Out rate in the next month you've
got a 4% you know what happened did did
you have a kind of a failure of a
release was there outage did your coupon
and promotion campaign not work out
exactly as expected by the way if you're
going to do those things that's fine but
if you're not in Customer Support
listening to this tell your customer
support people you're about to do a
promotion I I can't like the worst I
mean this is a common thing more in B2B
sales but in SAS which is sales gets the
Party Support gets the
hangover and I think same goes for
marketing if we're going to run a
campaign where we're going to put up a
billboard in in Time Square or an ad in
the Subway or a Super Bowl commercial
for God's sakes like you got to tell
your support team they may need to make
changes they need to staff accordingly
may need temporary people to hire so
that that's super important yeah funny
mentioned that cuz I I'm actually
currently doing support for my little
side project up and when we do a big
launch like I'm the guy at the keyboard
I mean for us a big launch is I get like
10 support emails and I can handle it in
like 30 minutes but still it's like
that's time out of my week that I have
to think about so anytime there's a big
launch I know that I'm kind of working
on the marketing side of things and and
going to be a little busier with that
and then I know I'm going to get get
some customer support from that launch
so I can't imagine you know I mean we're
just talking like thousands of new
downloads when when I do a little update
to my side project app but I can imagine
big launches big new campaigns changes
in promotion when you're at you know
millions or tens of millions of
downloads can really like dramatically
swing things so yeah definitely
something to be keeping in mind is there
any other metrics that you track around
like customer satisfaction or things
like that yeah so seat's a big one in
our industry also really helpful because
you want to Benchmark against other
similar businesses which is nice to do
but often you know a bit flawed we've
had CET on for a period of months off
for a period of months it really changes
it depends on the workflow and I used to
be a huge seat person which is just
customer satisfaction how would you rate
your you know your customer support
experience with the last agent you spoke
with one to five I actually don't care
as much about that number I mean sure
you want it to at least be a four out of
five or better what I look for and what
has been helpful for me is if you've got
a team of 10 and everyone's consistently
getting a 4.5 out of five and you've got
one person getting a 3.5 then that's
actually an indicator for you as a
manager to talk with that person and
find out what's going on do they not
understand the product are they feeling
rushed are is something going on in
their personal life so while that number
is really important to know it may find
its way onto a board deck for your
investors I think it's more it's it's a
better tool for me as a manager to have
an early warning sign of what may not be
working for a particular agent and I
have found that in the past and
sometimes you just find out there's
something personal going on in their
life and you say okay great now I know
like what can we do to make this better
can we make can we make changes to your
work schedule whatever it is so I
actually think about that more as a
comparative number to find out more
about your team yeah that makes sense
and then customer support is often kind
of the last line of defense for churn do
you track that or or how do you think
about kind of helping prevent churn as a
a customer support team cancellation and
churn is obviously on everyone's mind
especially inside of these walls we you
know we want downloads We want
conversions we want everyone to become a
full subscriber But ultimately it's not
right for everyone something may have
went wrong or again like maybe it just
wasn't right for the customer I feel
that cancellation and churn is on us
especially because I came from a
customer success background where you
can have a world where you have negative
churn which is essentially your
customers are either renewing at a
higher dollar value so it's actually
more than 100% of Revenue or it's
actually that you've lost some customers
but the overall customers have renewed
at a higher rate still resulting in
negative turn so that's a really
important number more for like
Enterprise SAS companies but from a
customer support perspective for a
mobile app and desktop app I really feel
that we are the last line of defense we
can have our own many winback campaigns
by having interactions with customers
where maybe you can do a winback
campaign with email or I think App Store
just came out with a new winb back
campaign right in the app store listing
which we still haven't tested I just
found it yesterday but yeah we we can
win back customers and I'm still trying
to figure out a way where I could comp
my team you know I'd like to be able to
reward my teammates who are not just
providing customer support but a little
bit of sales a little bit of customer
success I think if you can tie that back
in a meaningful way it'll also Empower
your agents to really feel like okay I
need to help this customer become come
back and yeah why not I mean it's a
great experience well one thing I've
done I don't know if if y'all are doing
this because I mean it could potentially
be really impactful at scale but anytime
I have a good customer experience and
support and again it's just me doing it
right now I did used to have it hired
out but the scale is just so small now
it doesn't make sense but after any good
customer experience with with support I
pretty much always ask for a rating and
or review and Link people right to it is
that something yall do as well and you
see see a lift from that yes I
definitely left that part out when I was
talking before ratings and reviews could
be the best thing in the world and the
most annoying thing because I can't tell
you how many customers say if you don't
fix this feature I'm going to give you a
one star or threaten us and say if you
don't fix this in you know in one minute
or if you don't give me a free version
I'll give you one star review I mean
what do you say to that I mean I think
Yelp probably Yelp and Trip Advisor
probably ruined the internet in terms of
operators being able to it really
penalizes a lot of the the good people
who are trying I'm like we're trying we
you know we've got half a dozen people
on support like we're here we're trying
but yes I mean asking customers to give
us App Store reviews and place reviews
is huge I always love it when we get an
apps for review and they shout out
someone on our team one of my agents and
they say Carl did an amazing job or
Marion did an amazing job or medy did an
amazing job if that happens screenshot
WR and C for
make them feel really good it's just
like it's a no-brainer and if people
start reading about great customer
support again another reason why people
might download the app in the first
place so it goes a long way what a
better way to like communicate how much
you care about your customers and that
kind of conier mindset than to see a
bunch of reviews talking about specific
support people in the App Store like
that's cool people right back and you
know a month later and they say hey can
you connect me back to medy I you know
like I want to talk to him again you
know people asking asking by name to
chat with people and that means that my
team did their job they built rapport
with this customer and I love to see
that how do you split or do you split
customer support by free versus paid
like do you offer the same amount of
support to free users this is a tricky
one I've thought about it a lot we don't
have a premium product we have a minimum
tier we have a three-day trial we've
tested 7day wasn't as good even though I
remember the report you put out last
year said 7day did better but not for us
I don't know why
but anyway we actually don't have free
customers although you can consider our
trial customers currently free or
non-revenue customers but you never know
when you're going to get a free customer
upgrade to your to the lowest tier or
you're going to have a middle tier
customer upgrade to your highest tier or
even downgrade to your lowest tier so we
treat all customers basically the same I
will say that if you're in that
experience where you've canceled a trial
or youve or you've CH we do bump you up
to like the front of the queue but again
we reply to customers so quickly I don't
know if it has a huge impact I think as
we scale if you ask me that question two
years from now I think we will probably
have to make some changes I think the
really the biggest difference are your
Enterprise customers and right now we've
got consumer customers we've got
prosumer customers and we're building
out services for Enterprise customers
we've got an API that's launched where
you can generate video you know
programmatically via API and get do some
really cool stuff those customers will
definitely be treated differently
because dollar value is way different
but 99% of our customers we basically
treat exactly the same well next up I
did actually want to get into tooling so
let's just kick that off with how do you
tell because you've kind of alluded to
this several times in the conversation
that you know when somebody is in their
free trial period you know when they're
in their free trial period and have
already canceled you know when they're
an active subscriber but have already
canceled how are you doing that what
tooling are you using to figure all that
out I don't know if this was a setup but
the one of the my answers is revenue C
that's no it wasn't a setup I didn't
think about that but yeah it makes sense
it makes sense yeah and I I'll explain
why so there's a lot of customer support
platforms out there we use intercom one
of the things that we get is that when
we install the intercom SDK on iOS
Android and desktop it passes along
information like their email address
what device they're on iPhone 12 vers 14
how many times they've opened the app
what iOS version they're on so we can
find out this information and if
customers have issues we need to know at
at least as much as they do we can't
know less so we we get that information
from intercom and then the other one
that we look at every time a customer
messages us on the right nav of the chat
there's three Revenue cat fields that
are sent automatically when a customer
message is us it's the latest
entitlement which means what plan
they're on it is their expiration date
which means when will their trial or
their subscription expire and then
what's their status are they currently
on auto renew or have they cancelled and
so those three things tell us a lot
about about our customers and we can
kind of shift our responses and change
our responses based on that information
and of course we've got three answers
one for apple one for Google one for
stripe as it comes to all of that so
that's really cool I actually didn't
know that you had all that hooked up
that way I think you and I talked about
this maybe like two years ago I think we
had to like build something for y'all to
get that done but I i' totally forgotten
that that was the case well this is a
great call back I guess because it's an
out-of-the-box integration with intercom
and revenue cat integrates with lots of
other tools but I did suggest that third
one that I mentioned of like are they on
auto renew or cancel that wasn't
available but your team actually did
build it for us so thank you very cool
so use intercom any other tooling that's
super important to all of this for for
tracking for AI agents and everything
else yeah I think our basically the
three tools is like your core chat
platform which we're using intercom and
I think is great they're also doing a
great job themselves with employing AI
both as like a agent co-pilot and
they've got their own agents and then I
think our AI agent that we use is called
parel been super impressed with the team
and what they've been able to do for us
and then lastly mfy this documentation
tool which is really meant for API docs
and API references the same way that
Revenue cat has your API docs maybe I'll
make a referral for you but it's really
clean it's really beautiful it's built
on GitHub the team's really great and we
have used that because we offer both
consumer customer support and we now
have API so now it's all in one place
which is really nice so if you if you
want to see what our our documentation
looked like just go to help. captions.
and you can check it out this has been
such a fun conversation starting from
like the philosophy of tech support and
like you know your kind of contrarian
views on that all the way through
talking about the tooling that like
makes that happen and hiring the folks
and scaling the team and all that wealth
of information for folks who are
struggling with this but anything I miss
anything else you wanted to share as we
wrap up just that it was great to see
you last week at app growth annual I've
got my bag right here great water bottle
but really it was an amazing event and
next year we will be submitting for the
shippies and I hope that we'll we'll be
presented with a Shippy but I I want to
bring one home for the team I don't
build this app Engineers product that it
takes like an entire team but it would
be very cool to reward everyone with
some recognition we'll see what happens
well it's a fantastic app and yeah it
was great seeing you and so many other
industry folks last week definitely
looking forward to next year we're going
to link to captions and to your LinkedIn
and other stuff anything else you wanted
to shout out for people who wanted to
get in touch or otherwise yeah if you
want to download the app and test out
our customer support and send your
thoughts to me give it a try captions. a
and then you can always find me on
LinkedIn Eli windbound I'm the only
one awesome well so much fun talking to
you today thank you thanks David thanks
so
much thanks so much for listening if you
have a minute please leave a review in
your favorite podcast player you can
also stop by chat. sub club.com to join
our private community